SUMMARY

Versatile, result driven, and multi-faceted professional with sharp analytical abilities and strong interpersonal skills. Received a degree in Computer Engineering and has industry experience in systems engineering, business development, marketing, as well as developing solutions for clients.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lockheed Martin

September 2015 – Present

Systems Engineer

Space Systems Company

- Identified technical objections, developed solutions, and proof of concept to increase business opportunities.
- Developed high-quality best total-solutions that fit customer strategic and operational requirements.
- Developed simulation models of 150+ nodes using different routing protocols as proof of concept.
- * Reviewed technical documents, requirements, and maintained our Linux servers.

IS&GS

- Worked closely with the engineers to determine which hardware updates will increase productivity and improve the automation to help reach customer's expectations.
- Wrote the deployment guide and other technical documents to deploy the solution for our customer.
- Streamlined configuration and process from local development environments to federal enterprise servers, which increased efficiency by 75%.
- ❖ Worked towards automating continuous integration from local environments to SharePoint Servers, which allowed developers to build and deploy solutions instantly to save time by 50%.
- Ongoing maintenance of the process and toolsets used to manage the software baseline, build, and release.

Verizon Enterprise Solutions - Federal Network Systems

June 2013 – August 2013

Procurement Summer Internship

- Developed a system to automate procurement documents by coding macros in Excel to increase efficiency by 50%, thus creating more time to satisfy customers with better-quality customer service.
- Evaluated and suggest product and service solutions in line with client needs and requirements.
- Presented with a team to co-workers on the benefits of using Microsoft SharePoint.

SYP Group, LLC

May 2011 – January 2012

IT Consultant Services

Network Engineer

- Acted as a strategic partner to my assigned clients and sold a broad range of advertising solutions that would ensure that their business goals were met.
- Diagnosed and resolved our client's servers, hardware, and network related issues.
- * Redesigned data network infrastructure and configured related hardware (VPN, routers, hubs, firewalls, CAT-5 wiring, etc).

EDUCATION

University of Maryland, Baltimore County (ABET Accredited)

Bachelors of Science, Computer Engineering

PROJECTS

Capstone Project: Luggage Tag Tracker

Fall 2014 – Spring 2015

Graduated: August 2015

- Worked with a team of four to design and create a luggage tag tracker for bags, luggage, or briefcase.
- Designed our system with an Arduino Uno microcontroller, Bluetooth (BLE 4.0), Wi-Fi, and GPS chip.
- As a group, we designed a mobile application for the tracker that retrieved the stored coordinates of the tracker from an encrypted cloud server.
- Wrote many technical documents, including: Team Status Reports, Systems Requirement Specification, and Statement of Work.

8086 Board Design Project

Spring 2014

- Worked with a team of four to design and program an 8086 Microprocessor System with memory, timers and interrupts.
- ❖ Designed a four-layer PCB layout for our 8086 Microprocessor using Cadence software.

SKILLS

- Operating Systems: Linux, CentOS, OS X, Windows, Windows Server 2012 R2
- Programming: Python, C, SDLC Methodologies, Configuration and Automation Management
- Software: JIRA, Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Photoshop, Wireshark, and Cloud Services (IaaS).

SECURITY CLEARANCE INFORMATION

BAPS International Organization, Beltsville, MD

Active: DoD Secret Clearance

ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS

. .

August 2010 - Present

Volunteer

Non-Profit Religious Organization

- Operating a custom 2D CNC Machine to cut precise shapes/designs out of foam. Creating vectors in ArtCam along with Adobe Illustrator.
- Currently volunteering in the construction of Akshardham in Robbinsville, New Jersey and enjoy working with my hands.